<?xml version="1.0"?>
<xml><segment><text>There are some variations possible, but it is commonly followed because of the  natural development cycle on which it is based. Especially when the requirements can be clearly  defined, waterfall model is an ideal model for development software. So let us see what  the different steps are.This diagram identifies different stages in the waterfall model. Let us look at each one  of them briefly. Then later on we will look at each of them in some more details. So the  first step is the system engineering step where you try to understand the overall problem  and identify which of the problem elements are to be handled through the software. It  is possible that certain requirements of the problem may need to be done manually, because  automation may not be possible whereas some other functions will be performed by the software.  So one of the goals in system engineering is to understand the overall context of the  problem. And then identify what would be the responsibilities to be met through the software.  After doing that we undertake the analysis phase. In the analysis phase we understand  the problem domain of the user in more detail. We understand what kind of information is  involved what kind of data is involved, what functions need to be performed, what are the  performance and interfacing requirements. This part is the analysis part whose purpose  is to identify or clearly define the requirements which are to be met thru the development of  the software along with. In the analysis we also try to carry out project  planning either as a part of the same step or if it is large project, the project planning  step may be made as a separate step. And the purpose of project planning is to identify  how we will carry out the project what are the different steps, what are the deliverables,  and what would be the time frame what could be the resources allocated. That is what a  project planning is all about.</text><question-answer-pair><question>What do waterfall methodologies result in a project schedule with in common practice?</question><answer>In common practice, waterfall methodologies result in a project schedule with 20 40 % of the time invested for the first two phases, 30 40 % of the time to coding, and the rest dedicated to testing and implementation.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What provides a structured approach; the model itself progresses linearly through discrete, easily understandable and explainable phases and thus is easy to understand?</question><answer>The waterfall model provides a structured approach; the model itself progresses linearly through discrete, easily understandable and explainable phases and thus is easy to understand; it also provides easily identifiable milestones in the development process.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is cheaper to fix than the same bug found later on in the process for example?</question><answer>For example, a problem found in the early stages (such as requirements specification) is cheaper to fix than the same bug found later on in the process (by a factor of 50 to 200).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>When can time spent early in the software production cycle reduce costs?</question><answer>Time spent early in the software production cycle can reduce costs at later stages.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do the detailed set of procedures and controls regulate every process on?</question><answer>Most medium and large projects will include a detailed set of procedures and controls, which regulate every process on the project.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is the waterfall model perhaps for?</question><answer>It is perhaps for this reason that the waterfall model is used as a beginning example of a development model in many software engineering texts and courses.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do the detailed set of procedures and controls regulate on the project?</question><answer>Most medium and large projects will include a detailed set of procedures and controls, which regulate every process on the project.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are projects where requirements and scope are fixed?</question><answer>It is argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed, the product itself is firm and stable, and the technology is clearly understood.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What regulate every process on the project?</question><answer>Most medium and large projects will include a detailed set of procedures and controls, which regulate every process on the project.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What can time spent early in the software production cycle reduce at later stages?</question><answer>Time spent early in the software production cycle can reduce costs at later stages.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>When can reduce costs at later stages?</question><answer>Time spent early in the software production cycle can reduce costs at later stages.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is that it places emphasis on documentation as well as source code?</question><answer>A further argument for the waterfall model is that it places emphasis on documentation (such as requirements documents and design documents) as well as source code.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What may be difficult for a project to recover from the loss?</question><answer>In less thoroughly designed and documented methodologies, knowledge is lost if team members leave before the project is completed, and it may be difficult for a project to recover from the loss.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What also provides easily identifiable milestones in the development process?</question><answer>The waterfall model provides a structured approach; the model itself progresses linearly through discrete, easily understandable and explainable phases and thus is easy to understand; it also provides easily identifiable milestones in the development process.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is a problem found in the early stages cheaper to fix than the same bug found later on in the process for?</question><answer>For example, a problem found in the early stages (such as requirements specification) is cheaper to fix than the same bug found later on in the process (by a factor of 50 to 200).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is a further argument for the waterfall model that it places as well as source code?</question><answer>A further argument for the waterfall model is that it places emphasis on documentation (such as requirements documents and design documents) as well as source code.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is a further argument for the waterfall model that it places emphasis on documentation as well as?</question><answer>A further argument for the waterfall model is that it places emphasis on documentation (such as requirements documents and design documents) as well as source code.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>If a fully working design document is present, who should be able to familiarise themselves by reading the documents?</question><answer>If a fully working design document is present (as is the intent of Big Design Up Front and the waterfall model), new team members or even entirely new teams should be able to familiarise themselves by reading the documents.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does the waterfall model provide itself progresses linearly through discrete, easily understandable and explainable phases and thus is easy to understand?</question><answer>The waterfall model provides a structured approach; the model itself progresses linearly through discrete, easily understandable and explainable phases and thus is easy to understand; it also provides easily identifiable milestones in the development process.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What did the same bug find later on in?</question><answer>For example, a problem found in the early stages (such as requirements specification) is cheaper to fix than the same bug found later on in the process (by a factor of 50 to 200).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is the waterfall model argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed itself is firm and stable?</question><answer>It is argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed, the product itself is firm and stable, and the technology is clearly understood.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What may the project be difficult for?</question><answer>In less thoroughly designed and documented methodologies, knowledge is lost if team members leave before the project is completed, and it may be difficult for a project to recover from the loss.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What found later on in the process?</question><answer>For example, a problem found in the early stages (such as requirements specification) is cheaper to fix than the same bug found later on in the process (by a factor of 50 to 200).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What needs to be highly structured?</question><answer>The actual project organization needs to be highly structured.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed itself is firm and stable?</question><answer>It is argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed, the product itself is firm and stable, and the technology is clearly understood.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is perhaps for this reason that the waterfall model is used as a beginning example of a development model in many software engineering texts and courses?</question><answer>It is perhaps for this reason that the waterfall model is used as a beginning example of a development model in many software engineering texts and courses.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are the product?</question><answer>It is argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed, the product itself is firm and stable, and the technology is clearly understood.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is clearly understood?</question><answer>It is argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed, the product itself is firm and stable, and the technology is clearly understood.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is a problem found in the early stages cheaper to fix than the same bug found later on in the process for example?</question><answer>For example, a problem found in the early stages (such as requirements specification) is cheaper to fix than the same bug found later on in the process (by a factor of 50 to 200).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do the detailed set of procedures and controls regulate every process on the project?</question><answer>Most medium and large projects will include a detailed set of procedures and controls, which regulate every process on the project.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Are projects where requirements and scope are fixed the product?</question><answer>It is argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed, the product itself is firm and stable, and the technology is clearly understood.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does the waterfall model also provide?</question><answer>The waterfall model provides a structured approach; the model itself progresses linearly through discrete, easily understandable and explainable phases and thus is easy to understand; it also provides easily identifiable milestones in the development process.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is it perhaps for?</question><answer>It is perhaps for this reason that the waterfall model is used as a beginning example of a development model in many software engineering texts and courses.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Can time spent early in the software production cycle reduce costs at later stages?</question><answer>Time spent early in the software production cycle can reduce costs at later stages.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is a further argument for the waterfall model that it places emphasis on documentation as well as source code?</question><answer>A further argument for the waterfall model is that it places emphasis on documentation (such as requirements documents and design documents) as well as source code.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is the waterfall model argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed is firm and stable?</question><answer>It is argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed, the product itself is firm and stable, and the technology is clearly understood.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>If a fully working design document is present, should new team members or even entirely new teams be able to familiarise themselves by reading the documents?</question><answer>If a fully working design document is present (as is the intent of Big Design Up Front and the waterfall model), new team members or even entirely new teams should be able to familiarise themselves by reading the documents.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Does the waterfall model provide a structured approach; the model itself progresses linearly through discrete, easily understandable and explainable phases and thus is easy to understand?</question><answer>The waterfall model provides a structured approach; the model itself progresses linearly through discrete, easily understandable and explainable phases and thus is easy to understand; it also provides easily identifiable milestones in the development process.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is it argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed is firm and stable?</question><answer>It is argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed, the product itself is firm and stable, and the technology is clearly understood.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is completed?</question><answer>In less thoroughly designed and documented methodologies, knowledge is lost if team members leave before the project is completed, and it may be difficult for a project to recover from the loss.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>May the project be difficult for a project to recover from the loss?</question><answer>In less thoroughly designed and documented methodologies, knowledge is lost if team members leave before the project is completed, and it may be difficult for a project to recover from the loss.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Does the waterfall model also provide easily identifiable milestones in the development process?</question><answer>The waterfall model provides a structured approach; the model itself progresses linearly through discrete, easily understandable and explainable phases and thus is easy to understand; it also provides easily identifiable milestones in the development process.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Does the actual project organization need to be highly structured?</question><answer>The actual project organization needs to be highly structured.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Did the same bug find later on in the process?</question><answer>For example, a problem found in the early stages (such as requirements specification) is cheaper to fix than the same bug found later on in the process (by a factor of 50 to 200).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is it argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed?</question><answer>It is argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed, the product itself is firm and stable, and the technology is clearly understood.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What result in a project schedule with 20 40 % of the time invested for the first two phases, 30 40 % of the time to coding, and the rest dedicated to testing and implementation in common practice?</question><answer>In common practice, waterfall methodologies result in a project schedule with 20 40 % of the time invested for the first two phases, 30 40 % of the time to coding, and the rest dedicated to testing and implementation.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do waterfall methodologies result in with 20 40 % of the time invested for the first two phases, 30 40 % of the time to coding, and the rest dedicated to testing and implementation in common practice?</question><answer>In common practice, waterfall methodologies result in a project schedule with 20 40 % of the time invested for the first two phases, 30 40 % of the time to coding, and the rest dedicated to testing and implementation.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do waterfall methodologies result in a project schedule with 20 40 % of the time invested for the first two phases, 30 40 % of the time to coding, and the rest dedicated to testing and implementation in?</question><answer>In common practice, waterfall methodologies result in a project schedule with 20 40 % of the time invested for the first two phases, 30 40 % of the time to coding, and the rest dedicated to testing and implementation.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is the waterfall model argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed?</question><answer>It is argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed, the product itself is firm and stable, and the technology is clearly understood.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What may it be difficult for?</question><answer>In less thoroughly designed and documented methodologies, knowledge is lost if team members leave before the project is completed, and it may be difficult for a project to recover from the loss.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does the waterfall model provide a structured approach; the model progresses linearly through discrete, easily understandable and explainable phases and thus is easy to understand?</question><answer>The waterfall model provides a structured approach; the model itself progresses linearly through discrete, easily understandable and explainable phases and thus is easy to understand; it also provides easily identifiable milestones in the development process.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is the technology clearly understood?</question><answer>It is argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed, the product itself is firm and stable, and the technology is clearly understood.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is a further argument for the waterfall model as?</question><answer>A further argument for the waterfall model is that it places emphasis on documentation (such as requirements documents and design documents) as well as source code.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is the project completed?</question><answer>In less thoroughly designed and documented methodologies, knowledge is lost if team members leave before the project is completed, and it may be difficult for a project to recover from the loss.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is it perhaps for this reason that the waterfall model is used as a beginning example of a development model in many software engineering texts and courses?</question><answer>It is perhaps for this reason that the waterfall model is used as a beginning example of a development model in many software engineering texts and courses.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does it also provide?</question><answer>The waterfall model provides a structured approach; the model itself progresses linearly through discrete, easily understandable and explainable phases and thus is easy to understand; it also provides easily identifiable milestones in the development process.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is it argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed itself is firm and stable?</question><answer>It is argued that the waterfall model can be suited to projects where requirements and scope are fixed, the product itself is firm and stable, and the technology is clearly understood.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does the waterfall model provide a structured approach; the model through?</question><answer>The waterfall model provides a structured approach; the model itself progresses linearly through discrete, easily understandable and explainable phases and thus is easy to understand; it also provides easily identifiable milestones in the development process.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>May it be difficult for a project to recover from the loss?</question><answer>In less thoroughly designed and documented methodologies, knowledge is lost if team members leave before the project is completed, and it may be difficult for a project to recover from the loss.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Does it also provide easily identifiable milestones in the development process?</question><answer>The waterfall model provides a structured approach; the model itself progresses linearly through discrete, easily understandable and explainable phases and thus is easy to understand; it also provides easily identifiable milestones in the development process.</answer></question-answer-pair></segment><segment><text>After the analysis is done, the next step leads to the design step. In the design step  we translate the requirements into the software architecture when we prepare the database  design and so on. So this is a primarily a technical step and in this step the requirements  are translated into an implementation framework, which will be implemented in the next phase  that is the coding phase, in which the actual programming and implementation will be done.  So you have a design and the design is followed by implementation.</text><question-answer-pair><question>What allows reuse of design components between projects?</question><answer>Documenting software architecture facilitates communication between stakeholders, captures decisions about the architecture design, and allows reuse of design components between projects.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does documenting software architecture allow reuse of?</question><answer>Documenting software architecture facilitates communication between stakeholders, captures decisions about the architecture design, and allows reuse of design components between projects.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What facilitates communication between stakeholders?</question><answer>Documenting software architecture facilitates communication between stakeholders, captures decisions about the architecture design, and allows reuse of design components between projects.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Who are captures decisions about the architecture design?</question><answer>Documenting software architecture facilitates communication between stakeholders, captures decisions about the architecture design, and allows reuse of design components between projects.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is about making fundamental structural choices which are costly to change once implemented?</question><answer>Software architecture is about making fundamental structural choices which are costly to change once implemented.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What could be made to have multiple redundant and independently produced copies of the program?</question><answer>Additionally, to satisfy the need for reliability the choice could be made to have multiple redundant and independently produced copies of the program, and to run these copies on independent hardware while cross-checking results.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What did the systems that controlled the space shuttle launch vehicle have the requirement of being very fast and very reliable for?</question><answer>For example, the systems that controlled the space shuttle launch vehicle had the requirement of being very fast and very reliable.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does documenting software architecture allow?</question><answer>Documenting software architecture facilitates communication between stakeholders, captures decisions about the architecture design, and allows reuse of design components between projects.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What did the systems that controlled the space shuttle launch vehicle have for example?</question><answer>For example, the systems that controlled the space shuttle launch vehicle had the requirement of being very fast and very reliable.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are stakeholders captures decisions about?</question><answer>Documenting software architecture facilitates communication between stakeholders, captures decisions about the architecture design, and allows reuse of design components between projects.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does documenting software architecture facilitate?</question><answer>Documenting software architecture facilitates communication between stakeholders, captures decisions about the architecture design, and allows reuse of design components between projects.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What were Software architecture choices also called?</question><answer>Software architecture choices, also called architectural decisions, include specific structural options from possibilities in the design of software.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What were also called architectural decisions?</question><answer>Software architecture choices, also called architectural decisions, include specific structural options from possibilities in the design of software.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What had the requirement of being very fast and very reliable for example?</question><answer>For example, the systems that controlled the space shuttle launch vehicle had the requirement of being very fast and very reliable.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What would need to be chosen?</question><answer>Therefore, an appropriate real-time computing language would need to be chosen.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What could be made to run these copies on independent hardware while cross-checking results?</question><answer>Additionally, to satisfy the need for reliability the choice could be made to have multiple redundant and independently produced copies of the program, and to run these copies on independent hardware while cross-checking results.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are stakeholders?</question><answer>Documenting software architecture facilitates communication between stakeholders, captures decisions about the architecture design, and allows reuse of design components between projects.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is Software architecture about making?</question><answer>Software architecture is about making fundamental structural choices which are costly to change once implemented.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Does documenting software architecture facilitate communication between stakeholders?</question><answer>Documenting software architecture facilitates communication between stakeholders, captures decisions about the architecture design, and allows reuse of design components between projects.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is Software architecture about making fundamental structural choices which are costly to change once implemented?</question><answer>Software architecture is about making fundamental structural choices which are costly to change once implemented.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Does documenting software architecture allow reuse of design components between projects?</question><answer>Documenting software architecture facilitates communication between stakeholders, captures decisions about the architecture design, and allows reuse of design components between projects.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Were Software architecture choices also called architectural decisions?</question><answer>Software architecture choices, also called architectural decisions, include specific structural options from possibilities in the design of software.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Did the systems that controlled the space shuttle launch vehicle have the requirement of being very fast and very reliable for example?</question><answer>For example, the systems that controlled the space shuttle launch vehicle had the requirement of being very fast and very reliable.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Would an appropriate real-time computing language need to be chosen?</question><answer>Therefore, an appropriate real-time computing language would need to be chosen.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Are stakeholders captures decisions about the architecture design?</question><answer>Documenting software architecture facilitates communication between stakeholders, captures decisions about the architecture design, and allows reuse of design components between projects.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Could the choice be made to have multiple redundant and independently produced copies of the program?</question><answer>Additionally, to satisfy the need for reliability the choice could be made to have multiple redundant and independently produced copies of the program, and to run these copies on independent hardware while cross-checking results.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Could the choice be made to run these copies on independent hardware while cross-checking results?</question><answer>Additionally, to satisfy the need for reliability the choice could be made to have multiple redundant and independently produced copies of the program, and to run these copies on independent hardware while cross-checking results.</answer></question-answer-pair></segment><segment><text>In fact as it notes here  the design itself may be divided into two stages called high level design and detailed  design. Again this would depend on the complexity of the task.  After you have done the implementation or carried out the programming phase, when the  individual units of the software are ready, you would get into the next phase called testing  phase and integration phase. In this all the individual pieces of the software are individually  first tested, and then the whole software is put together. The objective is to test  first the logic of individual modules.</text><question-answer-pair><question>What is a three-state logic gate a type of that can have three different outputs: high, low and high-impedance?</question><answer>A three-state logic gate is a type of logic gate that can have three different outputs: high, low and high-impedance.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What would mean the output is sourcing current from the positive power terminal in electronics?</question><answer>In electronics, a high output would mean the output is sourcing current from the positive power terminal (positive voltage).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What would mean the output is sinking current to the negative power terminal?</question><answer>A low output would mean the output is sinking current to the negative power terminal (zero voltage).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What would a high output mean is sourcing current from the positive power terminal in electronics?</question><answer>In electronics, a high output would mean the output is sourcing current from the positive power terminal (positive voltage).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are used on buses of the CPU to allow multiple chips to send data?</question><answer>These devices are used on buses of the CPU to allow multiple chips to send data.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What would High impedance mean that the output is effectively disconnected from?</question><answer>High impedance would mean that the output is effectively disconnected from the circuit.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What would a high output mean the output is sourcing current from the positive power terminal in?</question><answer>In electronics, a high output would mean the output is sourcing current from the positive power terminal (positive voltage).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What would a high output mean the output is sourcing current from in electronics?</question><answer>In electronics, a high output would mean the output is sourcing current from the positive power terminal (positive voltage).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What would mean that the output is effectively disconnected from the circuit?</question><answer>High impedance would mean that the output is effectively disconnected from the circuit.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What would a low output mean is sinking current to the negative power terminal?</question><answer>A low output would mean the output is sinking current to the negative power terminal (zero voltage).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is basically equivalent to a multiplexer?</question><answer>A group of three-states driving a line with a suitable control circuit is basically equivalent to a multiplexer, which may be physically distributed over separate devices or plug-in cards.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What may be physically distributed over separate devices or plug-in cards?</question><answer>A group of three-states driving a line with a suitable control circuit is basically equivalent to a multiplexer, which may be physically distributed over separate devices or plug-in cards.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What would a low output mean the output is sinking?</question><answer>A low output would mean the output is sinking current to the negative power terminal (zero voltage).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is a type of logic gate that can have three different outputs: high, low and high-impedance?</question><answer>A three-state logic gate is a type of logic gate that can have three different outputs: high, low and high-impedance.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is a group of three-states driving a line with a suitable control circuit basically equivalent to?</question><answer>A group of three-states driving a line with a suitable control circuit is basically equivalent to a multiplexer, which may be physically distributed over separate devices or plug-in cards.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What plays no role in the logic?</question><answer>The high-impedance state plays no role in the logic, which is strictly binary.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What may the multiplexer be physically distributed over?</question><answer>A group of three-states driving a line with a suitable control circuit is basically equivalent to a multiplexer, which may be physically distributed over separate devices or plug-in cards.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does the high-impedance state play?</question><answer>The high-impedance state plays no role in the logic, which is strictly binary.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is a three-state logic gate?</question><answer>A three-state logic gate is a type of logic gate that can have three different outputs: high, low and high-impedance.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What would a high output mean from in electronics?</question><answer>In electronics, a high output would mean the output is sourcing current from the positive power terminal (positive voltage).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Would a high output mean the output is sourcing current from the positive power terminal in electronics?</question><answer>In electronics, a high output would mean the output is sourcing current from the positive power terminal (positive voltage).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is a three-state logic gate a type of logic gate that can have three different outputs: high, low and high-impedance?</question><answer>A three-state logic gate is a type of logic gate that can have three different outputs: high, low and high-impedance.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What would High impedance mean from?</question><answer>High impedance would mean that the output is effectively disconnected from the circuit.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is strictly binary?</question><answer>The high-impedance state plays no role in the logic, which is strictly binary.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Would High impedance mean that the output is effectively disconnected from the circuit?</question><answer>High impedance would mean that the output is effectively disconnected from the circuit.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>May the multiplexer be physically distributed over separate devices or plug-in cards?</question><answer>A group of three-states driving a line with a suitable control circuit is basically equivalent to a multiplexer, which may be physically distributed over separate devices or plug-in cards.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What would a low output mean?</question><answer>A low output would mean the output is sinking current to the negative power terminal (zero voltage).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Would a low output mean the output is sinking current to the negative power terminal?</question><answer>A low output would mean the output is sinking current to the negative power terminal (zero voltage).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are these devices used on buses of the CPU to allow multiple chips to send?</question><answer>These devices are used on buses of the CPU to allow multiple chips to send data.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are these devices used on to allow multiple chips to send data?</question><answer>These devices are used on buses of the CPU to allow multiple chips to send data.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Does the high-impedance state play no role in the logic?</question><answer>The high-impedance state plays no role in the logic, which is strictly binary.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are these devices used on buses of the CPU to allow to send data?</question><answer>These devices are used on buses of the CPU to allow multiple chips to send data.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is a group of three-states driving a line with a suitable control circuit basically equivalent to a multiplexer?</question><answer>A group of three-states driving a line with a suitable control circuit is basically equivalent to a multiplexer, which may be physically distributed over separate devices or plug-in cards.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is the logic strictly binary?</question><answer>The high-impedance state plays no role in the logic, which is strictly binary.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Are these devices used on buses of the CPU to allow multiple chips to send data?</question><answer>These devices are used on buses of the CPU to allow multiple chips to send data.</answer></question-answer-pair></segment><segment><text>And then when we put all of them together we want  to test their interfaces, so that they work collectively in a manner in which they were  intended to work. This is the testing and integration phase  and this is followed by actual deployment of the software. Now the software is ready.  It is deployed and implemented. The user will take control and will start using the software.  After the deployment there is an ongoing maintenance phase.In the maintenance phase, we have to  make the necessary changes; if any errors are encountered we will have to remove the  errors. If the software is not meeting the performance requirements we may have to review  the software, may be we have to go back and look at the design whether the design can  be modified or if there is something else that can be done in order to improve the performance.  So this is an ongoing step which may generally be called a maintenance phase. And in this  phase, the software is either enhanced or is perfected or is ported to new hardware  or new machines.  This is an ongoing activity which needs to be done throughout the life time of the software.  These are the different phases through which a typical software development goes through.  We have identified here the main steps. Each of the steps has certain deliverable.  Let us enumerate the different deliverables which come out in a given sequence when we  perform these various steps.  One of the important deliverable is the project plan.</text><question-answer-pair><question>What is derived from the Latin portare''?</question><answer>The term ``port'' is derived from the Latin portare, meaning ``to carry''.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is the term ``port'' derived from''?</question><answer>The term ``port'' is derived from the Latin portare, meaning ``to carry''.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What must be ``carried'' to the new system?</question><answer>When code is not compatible with a particular operating system or architecture, the code must be ``carried'' to the new system.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What must the code be ``carried'' to?</question><answer>When code is not compatible with a particular operating system or architecture, the code must be ``carried'' to the new system.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Who often claim that the software they write is portable?</question><answer>Software developers often claim that the software they write is portable, meaning that little effort is needed to adapt it to a new environment.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is not compatible with a particular operating system or architecture?</question><answer>When code is not compatible with a particular operating system or architecture, the code must be ``carried'' to the new system.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is code not compatible with?</question><answer>When code is not compatible with a particular operating system or architecture, the code must be ``carried'' to the new system.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What means ``to carry''?</question><answer>The term ``port'' is derived from the Latin portare, meaning ``to carry''.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is the term ``port'' derived from the Latin portare''?</question><answer>The term ``port'' is derived from the Latin portare, meaning ``to carry''.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Must the code be ``carried'' to the new system?</question><answer>When code is not compatible with a particular operating system or architecture, the code must be ``carried'' to the new system.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Does the Latin portare mean ``to carry''?</question><answer>The term ``port'' is derived from the Latin portare, meaning ``to carry''.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do Software developers often claim that the software they write is portable?</question><answer>Software developers often claim that the software they write is portable, meaning that little effort is needed to adapt it to a new environment.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do Software developers often claim?</question><answer>Software developers often claim that the software they write is portable, meaning that little effort is needed to adapt it to a new environment.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is code not compatible with a particular operating system or architecture?</question><answer>When code is not compatible with a particular operating system or architecture, the code must be ``carried'' to the new system.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does the software they write mean to?</question><answer>Software developers often claim that the software they write is portable, meaning that little effort is needed to adapt it to a new environment.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What means that little effort is needed to adapt it to a new environment?</question><answer>Software developers often claim that the software they write is portable, meaning that little effort is needed to adapt it to a new environment.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Does the software they write mean that little effort is needed to adapt it to a new environment?</question><answer>Software developers often claim that the software they write is portable, meaning that little effort is needed to adapt it to a new environment.</answer></question-answer-pair></segment><segment><text>We will be carrying out the project  according to the plan that we make. Of course the plan needs to be revised periodically  as we progress through the project.  One of the deliverable could also be the feasibility report. The feasibility report is a report  which defines the cost effectiveness of the approach and the whole software project, whether  it is a good investment we are making, whether the software will be cost effective, whether  it will give the kind of benefits we are expecting from the software.</text><question-answer-pair><question>What develop recommended software standards such as XML, HTTP and HTML?</question><answer>Software standard organizations like the W3C, IETF develop recommended software standards such as XML, HTTP and HTML, so that software can interoperate through these standards.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do Software standard organizations like the W3C develop recommended?</question><answer>Software standard organizations like the W3C, IETF develop recommended software standards such as XML, HTTP and HTML, so that software can interoperate through these standards.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do a great variety of software companies and programmers in the world comprise?</question><answer>A great variety of software companies and programmers in the world comprise a software industry.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What include the Free Software Foundation, GNU Project and Mozilla Foundation?</question><answer>Non-profit software organizations include the Free Software Foundation, GNU Project and Mozilla Foundation.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is IETF?</question><answer>Software standard organizations like the W3C, IETF develop recommended software standards such as XML, HTTP and HTML, so that software can interoperate through these standards.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do non-profit software organizations include?</question><answer>Non-profit software organizations include the Free Software Foundation, GNU Project and Mozilla Foundation.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What comprise a software industry?</question><answer>A great variety of software companies and programmers in the world comprise a software industry.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is the W3C?</question><answer>Software standard organizations like the W3C, IETF develop recommended software standards such as XML, HTTP and HTML, so that software can interoperate through these standards.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do Software standard organizations like the W3C develop recommended software standards such as XML, HTTP and HTML?</question><answer>Software standard organizations like the W3C, IETF develop recommended software standards such as XML, HTTP and HTML, so that software can interoperate through these standards.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What often provide innovation?</question><answer>Other well-known large software companies include Oracle, Novell, SAP, Symantec, Adobe Systems, and Corel, while small companies often provide innovation.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do small companies often provide?</question><answer>Other well-known large software companies include Oracle, Novell, SAP, Symantec, Adobe Systems, and Corel, while small companies often provide innovation.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do non-profit software organizations include the Free Software Foundation, GNU Project and Mozilla Foundation?</question><answer>Non-profit software organizations include the Free Software Foundation, GNU Project and Mozilla Foundation.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do a great variety of software companies and programmers in the world comprise a software industry?</question><answer>A great variety of software companies and programmers in the world comprise a software industry.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is the W3C IETF?</question><answer>Software standard organizations like the W3C, IETF develop recommended software standards such as XML, HTTP and HTML, so that software can interoperate through these standards.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do small companies often provide innovation?</question><answer>Other well-known large software companies include Oracle, Novell, SAP, Symantec, Adobe Systems, and Corel, while small companies often provide innovation.</answer></question-answer-pair></segment><segment><text>So the project plan is one deliverable, feasibility report is another deliverable.  One of the important deliverable is requirements document which is also called software requirement  specification or SRS for short. SRS is very important baseline and defines the functions  that the software will perform for us.Obviously the SRS comes from the analysis step.  The next step is the design document. It defines the different components of the software and  how they will be implemented.You may have a detailed design document. This document  may specify individual units which will be implemented by different programmers.  We may have then specific test plans and expected test reports.What it implies is that testing  is not a on the fly kind of the task. Tests are planned well in advance.They define what  inputs will be given to the system and what outputs are expected and whether the expected  outputs are correct and the performance is as expected. So test plans are made well in  advance and as soon as the software is ready the test plans are carried out and the workability  of the software is demonstrated through the test plans.Of course the source code is an important deliverable and a deliverable which is in  executable form. Unlike other deliverables which are documents, this is a deliverable  which actually would be loaded on the computer and will be executed which actually defines  the software contents.  And then we will also have different types of manuals or documents which will be important  for users and for administration of the software, for installation of the software and so on.  So these different types of deliverables are identified from different stages or different  steps in the waterfall model.</text><question-answer-pair><question>What do Computer programmers often find helpful to review existing source code to learn about programming techniques?</question><answer>Computer programmers often find it helpful to review existing source code to learn about programming techniques.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Who often find source code helpful to review existing source code to learn about programming techniques?</question><answer>Computer programmers often find it helpful to review existing source code to learn about programming techniques.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What include binary translation and emulation of the original platform?</question><answer>Possible porting options include binary translation and emulation of the original platform.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do possible porting options include binary translation and emulation of?</question><answer>Possible porting options include binary translation and emulation of the original platform.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What consider source code an expressive artistic medium?</question><answer>Some people consider source code an expressive artistic medium.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is primarily used as input to the process that produces an executable program?</question><answer>Source code is primarily used as input to the process that produces an executable program (i. e. , it is compiled or interpreted).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do programmers frequently adapt source code from?</question><answer>Programmers frequently adapt source code from one piece of software to use in other projects, a concept known as software reusability.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is frequently cited as a contributing factor to the maturation of their programming skills?</question><answer>The sharing of source code between developers is frequently cited as a contributing factor to the maturation of their programming skills.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is generally computationally expensive without the source code for a particular piece of software?</question><answer>Without the source code for a particular piece of software, portability is generally computationally expensive.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Who frequently adapt source code from one piece of software to use in other projects known as software reusability?</question><answer>Programmers frequently adapt source code from one piece of software to use in other projects, a concept known as software reusability.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is source code primarily used as to the process that produces an executable program?</question><answer>Source code is primarily used as input to the process that produces an executable program (i. e. , it is compiled or interpreted).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is also used as a method of communicating algorithms between people?</question><answer>It is also used as a method of communicating algorithms between people (e. g. , code snippets in books).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Who can be used to generate source code?</question><answer>Decompilation of an executable program can be used to generate source code, either in assembly code or in a high-level language.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is portability generally computationally expensive without?</question><answer>Without the source code for a particular piece of software, portability is generally computationally expensive.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do possible porting options include?</question><answer>Possible porting options include binary translation and emulation of the original platform.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do programmers frequently adapt from one piece of software to use in other projects known as software reusability?</question><answer>Programmers frequently adapt source code from one piece of software to use in other projects, a concept known as software reusability.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is the sharing of source code between developers frequently cited as to the maturation of their programming skills?</question><answer>The sharing of source code between developers is frequently cited as a contributing factor to the maturation of their programming skills.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is the sharing of source code between developers frequently cited as a contributing factor to?</question><answer>The sharing of source code between developers is frequently cited as a contributing factor to the maturation of their programming skills.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is source code also used as?</question><answer>It is also used as a method of communicating algorithms between people (e. g. , code snippets in books).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is source code primarily used as input to?</question><answer>Source code is primarily used as input to the process that produces an executable program (i. e. , it is compiled or interpreted).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are a concept?</question><answer>Programmers frequently adapt source code from one piece of software to use in other projects, a concept known as software reusability.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are other projects?</question><answer>Programmers frequently adapt source code from one piece of software to use in other projects, a concept known as software reusability.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Who often find it helpful to review existing source code to learn about programming techniques?</question><answer>Computer programmers often find it helpful to review existing source code to learn about programming techniques.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do Computer programmers often find source code helpful to review existing source code to learn about programming techniques?</question><answer>Computer programmers often find it helpful to review existing source code to learn about programming techniques.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Can decompilation of an executable program be used to generate source code?</question><answer>Decompilation of an executable program can be used to generate source code, either in assembly code or in a high-level language.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do possible porting options include binary translation and emulation of the original platform?</question><answer>Possible porting options include binary translation and emulation of the original platform.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do some people consider source code an expressive artistic medium?</question><answer>Some people consider source code an expressive artistic medium.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is source code primarily used as input to the process that produces an executable program?</question><answer>Source code is primarily used as input to the process that produces an executable program (i. e. , it is compiled or interpreted).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is portability generally computationally expensive without the source code for a particular piece of software?</question><answer>Without the source code for a particular piece of software, portability is generally computationally expensive.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do programmers frequently adapt source code from one piece of software to use in other projects known as software reusability?</question><answer>Programmers frequently adapt source code from one piece of software to use in other projects, a concept known as software reusability.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is source code also used as a method of communicating algorithms between people?</question><answer>It is also used as a method of communicating algorithms between people (e. g. , code snippets in books).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Are other projects a concept?</question><answer>Programmers frequently adapt source code from one piece of software to use in other projects, a concept known as software reusability.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is it also used as?</question><answer>It is also used as a method of communicating algorithms between people (e. g. , code snippets in books).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is the sharing of source code between developers frequently cited as a contributing factor to the maturation of their programming skills?</question><answer>The sharing of source code between developers is frequently cited as a contributing factor to the maturation of their programming skills.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do Computer programmers often find it helpful to review existing source code to learn about programming techniques?</question><answer>Computer programmers often find it helpful to review existing source code to learn about programming techniques.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is it also used as a method of communicating algorithms between people?</question><answer>It is also used as a method of communicating algorithms between people (e. g. , code snippets in books).</answer></question-answer-pair></segment><segment><text>At the end of each step, if you recall we had said that every step ends in a validation  and verification step. Similarly in the waterfall model when we move from one step to another  there would be such reviews. Each step would end in a review.These review reports are  very important inputs for identifying whether the development proceeded as per the plans,  what ever the short comings whether the defects will were detected and were properly addressed.  So review report is basically a catalog of how the development went through and it is  an important input to the development team as well as to the management.  So these are different deliverables. Many of them are important of which SRS is obviously  one of the baseline. Design document is also very important for future maintenance. Source  code definitely is important as it is executable and without this user manual, installation  manual, some administration manuals and the system cannot be effectively used.  So as you see here these different documents are essential part of the software. So software  is not just the source code but all this documents which accompany software.  Now as we go through this waterfall model and we perform the different steps, naturally  we are investing more effort. The diagram shows the cost effort distribution as we run  through the different steps in the waterfall model. So there are different steps are shown  here. As you see that some of the earlier steps  have smaller effort than the subsequent steps.For example the detailed design implementation  is very effort intensive steps. The line here is a cumulative task and as you see it increases  rapidly as we progress in the development. Accumulated cost increases dramatically as  we go from initial steps to later steps. Because as we move along the steps we are committing  the time of programmers, technical people and computer time, all this is naturally a  cost factor.This effort distribution is important for us to understand. Because it clearly brings  out that we must take all efforts to remove errors as early as possible in the lifecycle.  We must discover and fix these errors as early as possible. Because fixing them subsequently  will be a very costly operation.So suppose there is a misunderstanding or  the analysis phase has not clearly identified the functional requirement, now that if it  is not detected at the review phase of the analysis, it would be carried over design,  detailed design and implementation. And it is possible that we discover that mistake  during the operational part of the software; when the users have started using the software.In order to make the correction we will have to undo the code design etcetera and go back  right up to the analysis phase and identify what was missed out what was wrongly understood,  and carry out the design and implementation and testing process again. So it is important  that such errors are captured as early as possible and they are not allowed to slip  into the subsequent steps.  So in any software development approach it is important to understand, how the cost and  efforts are distributed, not only for project planning, but for emphasizing an error free  activity in each step.  There are some shortcomings in the waterfall model. One of the main criticisms of waterfall  model is that it goes linearly and it assumes that all the requirements can be clearly defined  during the analysis phase. There are many situations where requirements may not be clearly  known. This often happens when there is no manual counterpart for the problem that we  are solving. If a manual counterpart exist, that means the function business function  is already been carried out manually and we are planning to automate that, then in this  case it is easy to define the requirements. But in a situation where there is no such  manual counterpart, when the system is been planned first time, then the requirements  may not be clearly known. Here is an example. We know that railway reservation has now been automated fully. Before that,  however the manual system existed. We knew what is the role or what are the tasks involved  in the railway reservation. You want to reserve a seat on the particular  train, you may want to cancel it, you may get waitlisted, waitlists have to be arranged  and there is a method for arranging. All those things were already defined as functional  activities.</text><question-answer-pair><question>What has become common practice to maintain code bases in version control systems?</question><answer>It has become common practice to maintain code bases in version control systems.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is the larger collection of all the source code of all the computer programs which make up the project?</question><answer>The code base of a computer programming project is the larger collection of all the source code of all the computer programs which make up the project.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What contain information about how the relationships among the source code files are to be compiled?</question><answer>These describe the relationships among the source code files, and contain information about how they are to be compiled.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What may be contained in a single file or many files?</question><answer>The source code for a particular piece of software may be contained in a single file or many files.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is the code base of a computer programming project?</question><answer>The code base of a computer programming project is the larger collection of all the source code of all the computer programs which make up the project.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is another tool frequently used by developers for source code maintenance?</question><answer>The revision control system is another tool frequently used by developers for source code maintenance.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What describe the relationships among the source code files?</question><answer>These describe the relationships among the source code files, and contain information about how they are to be compiled.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What might a program written primarily in the C programming language, have for optimization purposes for example?</question><answer>For example, a program written primarily in the C programming language, might have portions written in assembly language for optimization purposes.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What can be done at run time in some languages?</question><answer>In some languages, such as Java, this can be done at run time (each class is compiled into a separate file that is linked by the interpreter at runtime).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is a program also possible for linking?</question><answer>It is also possible for some components of a piece of software to be written and compiled separately, in an arbitrary programming language, and later integrated into the software using a technique called library linking.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What might have portions written in assembly language for optimization purposes for example?</question><answer>For example, a program written primarily in the C programming language, might have portions written in assembly language for optimization purposes.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What may the source code for a particular piece of software be contained in?</question><answer>The source code for a particular piece of software may be contained in a single file or many files.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What has the code base of a computer programming project become common practice to maintain?</question><answer>It has become common practice to maintain code bases in version control systems.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is the code base of a computer programming project the larger collection of?</question><answer>The code base of a computer programming project is the larger collection of all the source code of all the computer programs which make up the project.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What has the code base of a computer programming project become to maintain code bases in version control systems?</question><answer>It has become common practice to maintain code bases in version control systems.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are instructions included with the source code in?</question><answer>In these cases, instructions for compilations, such as a Makefile, are included with the source code.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What can be written in different programming languages?</question><answer>Though the practice is uncommon, a program's source code can be written in different programming languages.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What might a program written primarily in the C programming language, have portions written in assembly language for optimization purposes for?</question><answer>For example, a program written primarily in the C programming language, might have portions written in assembly language for optimization purposes.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What can also be stored in a database or elsewhere?</question><answer>Source code can also be stored in a database (as is common for stored procedures) or elsewhere.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What might a program written primarily in the C programming language, have portions written in assembly language for for example?</question><answer>For example, a program written primarily in the C programming language, might have portions written in assembly language for optimization purposes.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are carefully arranged into a directory tree?</question><answer>The source code which constitutes a program is usually held in one or more text files stored on a computer's hard disk; usually these files are carefully arranged into a directory tree, known as a source tree.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What can a program's source code be written in?</question><answer>Though the practice is uncommon, a program's source code can be written in different programming languages.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does the source code which constitutes a program is usually held in one or more text file stored on?</question><answer>The source code which constitutes a program is usually held in one or more text files stored on a computer's hard disk; usually these files are carefully arranged into a directory tree, known as a source tree.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is known as a source tree?</question><answer>The source code which constitutes a program is usually held in one or more text files stored on a computer's hard disk; usually these files are carefully arranged into a directory tree, known as a source tree.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are several, sometimes dozens or even hundreds of?</question><answer>Moderately complex software customarily requires the compilation or assembly of several, sometimes dozens or even hundreds, of different source code files.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is the directory tree known as?</question><answer>The source code which constitutes a program is usually held in one or more text files stored on a computer's hard disk; usually these files are carefully arranged into a directory tree, known as a source tree.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is the revision control system?</question><answer>The revision control system is another tool frequently used by developers for source code maintenance.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What customarily requires the compilation or assembly of several, sometimes dozens or even hundreds?</question><answer>Moderately complex software customarily requires the compilation or assembly of several, sometimes dozens or even hundreds, of different source code files.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is the code base of a computer programming project the larger collection of all the source code of all the computer programs which make up the project?</question><answer>The code base of a computer programming project is the larger collection of all the source code of all the computer programs which make up the project.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does moderately complex software customarily require the compilation or assembly of?</question><answer>Moderately complex software customarily requires the compilation or assembly of several, sometimes dozens or even hundreds, of different source code files.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What contain information about how they are to be compiled?</question><answer>These describe the relationships among the source code files, and contain information about how they are to be compiled.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>May the source code for a particular piece of software be contained in a single file or many files?</question><answer>The source code for a particular piece of software may be contained in a single file or many files.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are included with the source code in these cases?</question><answer>In these cases, instructions for compilations, such as a Makefile, are included with the source code.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is also possible for some components of a piece of software to be written and compiled separately language, and later integrated into the software using a technique called library linking?</question><answer>It is also possible for some components of a piece of software to be written and compiled separately, in an arbitrary programming language, and later integrated into the software using a technique called library linking.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does moderately complex software customarily require?</question><answer>Moderately complex software customarily requires the compilation or assembly of several, sometimes dozens or even hundreds, of different source code files.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Can a program's source code be written in different programming languages?</question><answer>Though the practice is uncommon, a program's source code can be written in different programming languages.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Can source code also be stored in a database or elsewhere?</question><answer>Source code can also be stored in a database (as is common for stored procedures) or elsewhere.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is the revision control system another tool frequently used by developers for source code maintenance?</question><answer>The revision control system is another tool frequently used by developers for source code maintenance.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is it also possible for linking?</question><answer>It is also possible for some components of a piece of software to be written and compiled separately, in an arbitrary programming language, and later integrated into the software using a technique called library linking.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What can this be done at in some languages?</question><answer>In some languages, such as Java, this can be done at run time (each class is compiled into a separate file that is linked by the interpreter at runtime).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are instructions included with in these cases?</question><answer>In these cases, instructions for compilations, such as a Makefile, are included with the source code.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What can this be done at run time in?</question><answer>In some languages, such as Java, this can be done at run time (each class is compiled into a separate file that is linked by the interpreter at runtime).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What has it become to maintain code bases in version control systems?</question><answer>It has become common practice to maintain code bases in version control systems.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Might a program written primarily in the C programming language, have portions written in assembly language for optimization purposes for example?</question><answer>For example, a program written primarily in the C programming language, might have portions written in assembly language for optimization purposes.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are of different source code files?</question><answer>Moderately complex software customarily requires the compilation or assembly of several, sometimes dozens or even hundreds, of different source code files.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Has the code base of a computer programming project become common practice to maintain code bases in version control systems?</question><answer>It has become common practice to maintain code bases in version control systems.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What has it become common practice to maintain?</question><answer>It has become common practice to maintain code bases in version control systems.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is uncommon?</question><answer>Though the practice is uncommon, a program's source code can be written in different programming languages.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Does the source code which constitutes a program is usually held in one or more text file stored on a computer's hard disk?</question><answer>The source code which constitutes a program is usually held in one or more text files stored on a computer's hard disk; usually these files are carefully arranged into a directory tree, known as a source tree.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is the directory tree known as a source tree?</question><answer>The source code which constitutes a program is usually held in one or more text files stored on a computer's hard disk; usually these files are carefully arranged into a directory tree, known as a source tree.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What files stored on a computer's hard disk?</question><answer>The source code which constitutes a program is usually held in one or more text files stored on a computer's hard disk; usually these files are carefully arranged into a directory tree, known as a source tree.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Does moderately complex software customarily require the compilation or assembly of several, sometimes dozens or even hundreds?</question><answer>Moderately complex software customarily requires the compilation or assembly of several, sometimes dozens or even hundreds, of different source code files.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do these describe?</question><answer>These describe the relationships among the source code files, and contain information about how they are to be compiled.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Are several, sometimes dozens or even hundreds of different source code files?</question><answer>Moderately complex software customarily requires the compilation or assembly of several, sometimes dozens or even hundreds, of different source code files.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What are these files carefully arranged into?</question><answer>The source code which constitutes a program is usually held in one or more text files stored on a computer's hard disk; usually these files are carefully arranged into a directory tree, known as a source tree.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do these contain?</question><answer>These describe the relationships among the source code files, and contain information about how they are to be compiled.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is the practice uncommon?</question><answer>Though the practice is uncommon, a program's source code can be written in different programming languages.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do these contain information about how the relationships among the source code files are to be compiled?</question><answer>These describe the relationships among the source code files, and contain information about how they are to be compiled.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do these contain information about how they are to be compiled?</question><answer>These describe the relationships among the source code files, and contain information about how they are to be compiled.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do these describe the relationships among the source code files?</question><answer>These describe the relationships among the source code files, and contain information about how they are to be compiled.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Can this be done at run time in some languages?</question><answer>In some languages, such as Java, this can be done at run time (each class is compiled into a separate file that is linked by the interpreter at runtime).</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Has it become common practice to maintain code bases in version control systems?</question><answer>It has become common practice to maintain code bases in version control systems.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Are instructions included with the source code in these cases?</question><answer>In these cases, instructions for compilations, such as a Makefile, are included with the source code.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is a program also possible for some components of a piece of software to be written and compiled separately language, and later integrated into the software using a technique called library linking?</question><answer>It is also possible for some components of a piece of software to be written and compiled separately, in an arbitrary programming language, and later integrated into the software using a technique called library linking.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Are these files carefully arranged into a directory tree?</question><answer>The source code which constitutes a program is usually held in one or more text files stored on a computer's hard disk; usually these files are carefully arranged into a directory tree, known as a source tree.</answer></question-answer-pair></segment><segment><text>And therefore one can say that as far as the railway reservation is concerned  the manual system existed, and therefore it is possible to clearly define the requirements  in this case.  But there can be other examples where there may be no manual counterpart.For example, say a central bank wants to build a knowledge management system. It believes  that there is so much knowledge that is available with its employees in order to carry out their  day to day task. It would like to capture this knowledge, build a repository, so that  this knowledge is easily available to all other people in the organization.  Now this is something which is quite new and it is difficult to define a SRS for an application  like this. There is obviously some kind of uncertainty involved in terms of what it will  consists of.</text><question-answer-pair><question>What s central-bank assets are controlled by four centers in China, the United States, Japan and the eurozone?</question><answer>As of 2016,75 % of the world s central-bank assets are controlled by four centers in China, the United States, Japan and the eurozone.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does 75 % of the world s are controlled by four centers in China, the United States, Japan and the eurozone?</question><answer>As of 2016,75 % of the world s central-bank assets are controlled by four centers in China, the United States, Japan and the eurozone.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do the central banks of Brazil account for?</question><answer>The central banks of Brazil, Switzerland, Saudi Arabia, the U. K. , India and Russia, each account for an average of 2. 5 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>When did largest central banks own $21. 4 trillion in assets?</question><answer>According to data compiled by Bloomberg News, the top 10 largest central banks owned $21. 4 trillion in assets, a 10 percent increase from 2015.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does 75 % of the world s central-bank assets are controlled by?</question><answer>As of 2016,75 % of the world s central-bank assets are controlled by four centers in China, the United States, Japan and the eurozone.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What account for an average of 2. 5 percent?</question><answer>The central banks of Brazil, Switzerland, Saudi Arabia, the U. K. , India and Russia, each account for an average of 2. 5 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is Saudi Arabia?</question><answer>The central banks of Brazil, Switzerland, Saudi Arabia, the U. K. , India and Russia, each account for an average of 2. 5 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>How many remaining central banks hold less than 13 percent?</question><answer>The remaining 107 central banks hold less than 13 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is India and Russia?</question><answer>The central banks of Brazil, Switzerland, Saudi Arabia, the U. K. , India and Russia, each account for an average of 2. 5 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is the U. K.?</question><answer>The central banks of Brazil, Switzerland, Saudi Arabia, the U. K. , India and Russia, each account for an average of 2. 5 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What did largest central banks own from 2015?</question><answer>According to data compiled by Bloomberg News, the top 10 largest central banks owned $21. 4 trillion in assets, a 10 percent increase from 2015.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What was Bloomberg News?</question><answer>According to data compiled by Bloomberg News, the top 10 largest central banks owned $21. 4 trillion in assets, a 10 percent increase from 2015.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is Switzerland?</question><answer>The central banks of Brazil, Switzerland, Saudi Arabia, the U. K. , India and Russia, each account for an average of 2. 5 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What do the remaining 107 central banks hold?</question><answer>The remaining 107 central banks hold less than 13 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What hold less than 13 percent?</question><answer>The remaining 107 central banks hold less than 13 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Who was the top 10?</question><answer>According to data compiled by Bloomberg News, the top 10 largest central banks owned $21. 4 trillion in assets, a 10 percent increase from 2015.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What does 75 % of the world s by?</question><answer>As of 2016,75 % of the world s central-bank assets are controlled by four centers in China, the United States, Japan and the eurozone.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is Brazil?</question><answer>The central banks of Brazil, Switzerland, Saudi Arabia, the U. K. , India and Russia, each account for an average of 2. 5 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What was $21. 4 trillion in assets?</question><answer>According to data compiled by Bloomberg News, the top 10 largest central banks owned $21. 4 trillion in assets, a 10 percent increase from 2015.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Does 75 % of the world s central-bank assets are controlled by four centers in China, the United States, Japan and the eurozone?</question><answer>As of 2016,75 % of the world s central-bank assets are controlled by four centers in China, the United States, Japan and the eurozone.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What owned $21. 4 trillion in assets from 2015?</question><answer>According to data compiled by Bloomberg News, the top 10 largest central banks owned $21. 4 trillion in assets, a 10 percent increase from 2015.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What is each?</question><answer>The central banks of Brazil, Switzerland, Saudi Arabia, the U. K. , India and Russia, each account for an average of 2. 5 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is Brazil Saudi Arabia?</question><answer>The central banks of Brazil, Switzerland, Saudi Arabia, the U. K. , India and Russia, each account for an average of 2. 5 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is Brazil the U. K.?</question><answer>The central banks of Brazil, Switzerland, Saudi Arabia, the U. K. , India and Russia, each account for an average of 2. 5 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is Brazil India and Russia?</question><answer>The central banks of Brazil, Switzerland, Saudi Arabia, the U. K. , India and Russia, each account for an average of 2. 5 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do the central banks of Brazil account for an average of 2. 5 percent?</question><answer>The central banks of Brazil, Switzerland, Saudi Arabia, the U. K. , India and Russia, each account for an average of 2. 5 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What was a 10 percent increase?</question><answer>According to data compiled by Bloomberg News, the top 10 largest central banks owned $21. 4 trillion in assets, a 10 percent increase from 2015.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is Brazil Switzerland?</question><answer>The central banks of Brazil, Switzerland, Saudi Arabia, the U. K. , India and Russia, each account for an average of 2. 5 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Was Bloomberg News the top 10?</question><answer>According to data compiled by Bloomberg News, the top 10 largest central banks owned $21. 4 trillion in assets, a 10 percent increase from 2015.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Do the remaining 107 central banks hold less than 13 percent?</question><answer>The remaining 107 central banks hold less than 13 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Is Brazil each?</question><answer>The central banks of Brazil, Switzerland, Saudi Arabia, the U. K. , India and Russia, each account for an average of 2. 5 percent.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Did largest central banks own $21. 4 trillion in assets from 2015?</question><answer>According to data compiled by Bloomberg News, the top 10 largest central banks owned $21. 4 trillion in assets, a 10 percent increase from 2015.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Was $21. 4 trillion in assets a 10 percent increase?</question><answer>According to data compiled by Bloomberg News, the top 10 largest central banks owned $21. 4 trillion in assets, a 10 percent increase from 2015.</answer></question-answer-pair></segment><segment><text>So this is clearly one issue when we try to  apply for the waterfall model, which the requirements may not be clearly known and it may not be  possible to carry out analysis phase once for all and then never come back for revising  the requirements.  The other issue is that the waterfall model assumes that the requirements are quite stable  and that they do not change with time. Now, this is not the case because the software  development itself may be a long process, requiring months or years and during this  time one cannot assume that the requirements will not change.  So in the process what may happen is that when the software is finally built, the users  may find that it does not meet their requirements. In such a situation it is probably a good  idea to develop the software in parts or in smaller increments and then release them and  get the feedback of the user.  So there may be different approaches rather than using a strictly linear waterfall model  in such situations.</text><question-answer-pair><question>What can various modified waterfall models include?</question><answer>Various modified waterfall models (including Royce's final model), however, can include slight or major variations on this process.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What can include slight or major variations on this process?</question><answer>Various modified waterfall models (including Royce's final model), however, can include slight or major variations on this process.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What were found downstream?</question><answer>These variations included returning to the previous cycle after flaws were found downstream, or returning all the way to the design phase if downstream phases deemed insufficient.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Were flaws found downstream?</question><answer>These variations included returning to the previous cycle after flaws were found downstream, or returning all the way to the design phase if downstream phases deemed insufficient.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Can various modified waterfall models include slight or major variations on this process?</question><answer>Various modified waterfall models (including Royce's final model), however, can include slight or major variations on this process.</answer></question-answer-pair></segment><segment><text>Waterfall model is also considered very documentation-heavy, what  it means is that too much documentation is being produced as part of the project.  This may not be really necessary in all types of projects. So other models have been proposed  in order to take care of some of the short comings or to handle some specific situations  in project development scenarios.  One of them is the prototyping model. In the prototyping model we try to build a prototype  rather than the final solution. And we do this especially when the customer is either  not aware of his requirements that what exactly he would like to how the software would do  for him. Or the developer is not sure about how to develop the software, how to implement  the business rules which are generally required for the software. So he may not be certain  about the best algorithms that need to be implemented in order to meet the requirements.  Or if efficiency is primary criteria, we are trying to let us say build software which  will give very high response time, then what kind of techniques one should use in order  to guarantee that kind of efficiency or response time.</text><question-answer-pair><question>When did no formal software development methodologies exist?</question><answer>Because no formal software development methodologies existed at the time, this hardware-oriented model was simply adapted for software development.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What was simply adapted for software development?</question><answer>Because no formal software development methodologies existed at the time, this hardware-oriented model was simply adapted for software development.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What existed at the time?</question><answer>Because no formal software development methodologies existed at the time, this hardware-oriented model was simply adapted for software development.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Did no formal software development methodologies exist at the time?</question><answer>Because no formal software development methodologies existed at the time, this hardware-oriented model was simply adapted for software development.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>What was this hardware-oriented model simply adapted for?</question><answer>Because no formal software development methodologies existed at the time, this hardware-oriented model was simply adapted for software development.</answer></question-answer-pair><question-answer-pair><question>Was this hardware-oriented model simply adapted for software development?</question><answer>Because no formal software development methodologies existed at the time, this hardware-oriented model was simply adapted for software development.</answer></question-answer-pair></segment></xml>
